It takes about 3 months and everything
going exactly right for this wafer to
become a chip. And in all that time, no
human will ever touch it.
Robots move the wafers along the ceiling
to keep them safe.
>> You have some of the largest factories
that are making some of the world's
smallest features.
>> From start to finish, the wafer will
travel hundreds of miles on these tracks
as it turns into a chip.
>> And it'll move along, it'll stop at a
tool, do some processing, and then when
that's done, it'll go back up and then
it'll it'll move to the next step.
>> The work has gotten more intricate over
the years. Chips these days are barely
bigger than a fingernail.
That's why there's literally no room for
error.
>> You have about 2,000 steps and you need
every step to be perfect.
>> A bump or ridge in the silicon can
interfere with the patterns they have to
make, which is why the wafer visits this
machine to get flatter and flatter until
it's quite literally one of the flattest
things ever made.
>> And so any vibration, you and I walking
by, the tool next to it vibrating, can
impact the process. And if you look at
all of these tools, they actually sit on
top of a pedestal.
>> The whole factory is engineered to
barely move. Its foundation uses twice
as much concrete as the Burj Khalifa,
the world's tallest building.
Because if this place shakes, it's not
just a few dozen wafers that get
destroyed.
Tens of thousands of wafers are at risk.
>> Yeah, the automation that you have keep
track of where each lot is and what it
needs to do next is a whole art form in
itself.
>> When they add a new layer to a wafer,
they often have to send it back to
machines like this one, which polishes
the surface and clears away anything
that doesn't belong. The layer they're
building next holds one of the most
important parts of the chip, the
transistor.
>> So, what are we actually able to see
here?
>> You see the wires that connect each of
the transistors to each other.
>> Just one of these squares contains 10
billion transistors.
They are microscopic
and work like an electric switch that
turns on and off.
The closer you pack the transistors
together,
the faster the current can travel
throughout the chip and the less power
it uses, which makes the chip more
valuable.
>> Uh very much how you would build a city,
you know, with very tall skyscrapers. We
will put layer upon layer of these
skyscrapers up. Uh if you stacked 10,000
of them one on top of another, it'd be
thinner than a sheet of of a piece of
paper.